Welcome to introduction to machine learning lesson.
I'm excited to be your instructor for this section.
Machine learning is creating reckless and exciting changes across all levels of society,
it's the engine behind the recent advancement in autonomous vehicles.
It allows for a more accurate and rapid translation of text into hundreds of languages,
and it powers the AI assistants you might find in your home.
We can also use machine learning to do things like improving
worker safety and a speeding up drug discovery.
Machine learning Is a complex subject area.
Our goal in this lesson is introduce you to some of
the most common terms and ideas used in machine learning.
I would then walk you through the different steps involved in machine learning,
and finish with a series of examples which
use machine learning to solve real-world situations.
There are a lot to cover. Let's get started.