You have learned about the tasks of machine learning workflow.
Now, let's see what this actually looks like in real life.
We are going to look at three case studies showing three types of machine learning tasks.
Supervised learning task, where we tried to predict housing prices for
homes in your neighborhood based on lot size and number of bedrooms.
Unsupervised learning task where we try to use machine learning to find
interesting collections of books in
a book dataset based on descriptive words in the book description.
Finally, we will see a third case study where we use a more modern model called a
deep neural network to try to detect chemical spills in a lab from video and images.
While neural networks are beyond the scope of this lesson,
we felt it's worthwhile to touch on how they work.