Let's explore a second example.
You do editorial work for
a book recommendation company and you want
to write an article on the largest book trends of the year.
You are aware of trends, describe that, microgenres.
For example, Teen Vampire romance novels.
You have high confidence that other microgenres
exist and you believe that words and phrases used
in the back of the book description might provide
some guidance on which microgenre a book belongs to.
You think you can use machine learning to explore
whether books can be grouped together in this way.
You anticipate that books with similar content use similar words on the back of the book.
You've seen that, microgenres might be represented as
groups of books whose description use very similar words.
You will define the problem as,
let's find the clusters of similar books based on presence of certain words.
Earlier in this lesson we discussed unsupervised learning.
Remember this is especially useful if our data is not labeled.
You decide to use an unsupervised machine learning called
clustering approach to explore this proposed structure.
Data collection.
You collect back of book texts for 800 Romans books published in the current year.
Because you don't think capitalization and
verb tense matter for this structure you propose,
you remove capitals and convert all verbs to the same text.
For this, you can even use Python library built for processing human language.
You also remove punctuation and words you don't think have useful meaning like a and the.
Data vectorization is a process which turns the words into numbers.
You transform this backup book texts into what is called a bag-of-words representation,
which is understandable by machine learning maps.
How bag-of-words works is beyond the scope of this course,
but in this image here,
you can see it just transforms,
it takes into sequence of numbers.
Through some Internet searching,
you determine the clustering model called
k-means is a good first choice because it's simple and general purpose.
The k in k-means,
defines how many clusters the model will fight.
You don't know how many microgenres exist,
so you run model training for multiple values of k,
let's say 2, 3,
all the way up to 40,
and plan when choosing the best one during model evaluation.
What does this look like?
In this example, you can see k equal two clusters,
and here is k equal three clusters.
When evaluating machine learning models,
there are many options for the statistical metrics you can
use to help determine how effective your model is.
Most of these metrics are beyond the scope of this lesson,
but as you start to use machine learning,
you will learn to research and identify
these metrics to help you evaluate your model most effectively.
In this case, silhouette coefficient will serve as well.
We are back to our example.
Silhouette coefficient is a common metric for
determining how well your data was clustered.
You plot a silhouette coefficient for each model you trained
in their previous step and observe some sudden point of
diminishing returns as you increase k. It
seems as if you have identified k equal 19 clusters here.
Through Quakers spot checking,
you see one cluster within this model contains a large collection of
book which you categorize as paranormal teen dramas.
Because this is a noun trend in your industry in the present here,
you feel somewhat confident in your machine learning approach.
You don't know if every cluster is going to be as cohesive as this,
but you decide to use this model to see if you
can find anything interesting to write an article about.
You find a surprisingly large cluster of books,
cluster number 7, shown here,
where the people are in a long distance relationship.
Mission accomplished.
You see a few other self-consistent clusters and feel
you now have enough useful data to begin writing an article on.
Maybe you can title the article,
unexpected model, romance microgenres.