Let's review example number 3.
In the past examples,
we use classical methods like linear models and k-means to solve machine learning tasks.
In this example, we will see a more modern model type.
You run a company which offers a specialized on-site janitorial services.
One of your clients and industrial chemical plant
requires fast response for spills and other health hazards.
You realize you should be able to mobilize your janitorial team
faster if you could detect the spills from the plant surveillance system.
You investigate using machine learning to perform this automatic detection.
You recognize you can represent this task as a supervised classification task.
Your goal will be to predict if each image belongs to a,
contains a spill class or it does not contain a spill class.
Since you run the janitorial service,
it's pretty easy for you to stage safe for spills.
You quickly build a collection of images that contain
both the spills and non spills in multiple lighting conditions and environments.
Exploring and cleaning your dataset is pretty straightforward.
You quickly flip through all photos to ensure the spill is clearly in shut.
You split the images into a training dataset and test dataset.
The surveillance system produces only grayscale images.
You convert the image to numeric data so the model can process the data.
To demonstrate this, in this example of a dark liquidus spill,
you can see each pixel in the image on the left can be
represented in the image on the right by a number between zero and one.
Zero being completely black and one being completely white.
Traditionally to solve this problem,
a human would have to manually label the features in the image.
For example, locations are prominent,
edges and corners in the image,
and then train a model on these features.
Today, deep neural networks are the most commonly used tool for the problems like this.
These deep neural networks can learn
the features in an image as long as they have been labeled.
CNN or Convolutional Neural Network,
which is a common deep learning model for processing image,
is a good model choice for this task.
These neural networks are made up of many different types of layers.
These layers are required for neural networks to train successfully.
The details of neural networks are beyond the scope of this lesson,
but we wanted to at least introduce the idea.
We will keep things high level for now.
You begin training to solve your classification task here.
As we saw in our last example,
there are also many options for the statistical metrics you can
use to help determine how effective your neural network model is.
As you further explore machine learning,
you will learn to research and identify these metrics
and learn which one help you evaluate your model most effectively.
As we will see here,
precision and recall will be effective in this example.
You stop and realize that accuracy might not be the best evaluation mechanism.
Defined as percentage of correct predictions,
you realize the model will see the newest spill class almost all the time.
Any model that just predicts no spill most of the time will be pretty accurate.
What you really care is an evaluation mechanism that really misses a real spill.
After doing some Internet search,
you realize this is a common problem.
You augment your accuracy valuation mechanism with
the evaluation metrics, precision and recall.
You can think of precision as answering the question,
of all predictions of a spill how many were right?
Or in this example,
how often will I be sending a janitor to clean an actual spill?
You can think of recall as answering the question of all actual spills,
how many did we detect?
Or in this example,
how many of these spills did my system catch?
You also realize your [inaudible] spills might not have been sufficiently
realistic and you really want to have
a good sense of how well your model will do when you use it.
You spend an hour searching through historical records of
the surveillance system and find a few cases are real spills.
You evaluate your model against this dataset
and convert that into performing satisfactorily.
Confident in these results,
you deploy this model on a system that enables
you to run machine-learning workloads on surveillance systems.
You implement a simple paging system and begin transitioning
your team to respond to these pages in addition to the typical routines.