Congratulations on completing this lesson.
We went through a lot of information to give you
a foundational understanding of machine learning.
Hopefully you now have a better sense of what machine learning is.
Let's look back and see what we covered.
We discussed machine learning as a complex subject area to understand what
machine learning is and what are
the common components involved in machine learning project.
We also introduced you to
some most common terms and ideas that are used in machine learning.
We discussed how machine learning involves using train models
to generate predictions and detect patterns from data.
We looked a bit behind the scenes
to break down the different steps involved in machine learning.
In this section, we took you through a couple of
real-world examples which use machine learning
in different ways to solve real-world problems.