Now we can finally start training our model.
One quicker step before training your model is splitting your dataset.
You need to randomly split the dataset,
keeping some of the data hidden from training.
This enables you to later evaluate
your model with the data before it's put into production.
A training dataset is a data that will be used when your model is training.
Most of your data will be here.
A general rule of thumb is around 80 percent of your data.
There's also a test dataset.
This is the data that the model hasn't seen during training.
It's used during the model evaluation state.
It helps you see how well your model will generalize to new data.
As you learn more about machine learning,
there are additional components such as validation data.
Those are outside the scope of this lesson,
but just keep them in mind.
What exactly is model training?
Let us start with a general definition.
The model training algorithm iteratively
updates a model parameters to minimize some loss function.
Let's unpack that one.
Model parameters are sitting knobs or configurations
that the training algorithm can update to change how the model behaves.
Depending on context, you will also hear
other more specific terms used to describe model parameters,
such as weights or biases.
Taking a look at this snow cone example,
since we were trying to fit a linear function to this data,
the parameters would be the orientation and location of the line.
Nearly all models are trained by a slowly changing
model parameters to move the model closer and closer to achieving some goal.
A loss function is used to codify the model's distance from the score.
For example, if you were trying to predict
number of a snow cone sales based on the day's weather,
you care about making predictions which are as accurate as possible.
You might define a loss function to be something like the average distance
between your models predicted number of snow console and the actual number.
Here is a concrete example.
Imagine that your model predicts you would sell
12 snow cones on a day where the temperature is 95.
Our historical data shows the number of snow cones sold is 15.
The difference between 12 snow cones predicted and 15 actual snow cones sold,
which is, as you can see is 3,
is what the loss function seeks to minimize.
In practice, you will likely use one of several common loss function for most problems.
Of course, there are plenty of other details involved in the process.
This touch on a few high-level questions you might have and a few useful things to know.
As you grow your familiarity with this space,
you will learn a few common model training algorithm.
You could absolutely implement these from scratch.
But unless you're developing brand new models or algorithm,
you will likely use one of many machine learning frameworks,
which already have these implemented for you.
Determining which model to use.
A process known as model selection is not a perfect science.
The list of established model is constantly growing and even seasoned machine learning
practitioners will try many different types of
models while solving your problem with machine learning.
Within this course, you will see a few types of models at the end
of this lesson while walking through some real-world example.
Oftentimes a model or a training algorithm will have settings called hyperparameters,
which cannot be changed during model training.
These settings can affect how quickly or how reliably the model trains.
You will see this across many steps in this process,
but be prepared to iterate.
Pragmatic problem-solving with machine learning is really an exact science.
Often you might have assumptions about your data or assumptions about the problem,
which turn out not to be true.
Don't get discouraged.
Instead, foster habit of trying new things and
measure success in a way that lets you compare results across iterations.