After we have collected our dataset and trained our model,
we are ready to actually see how well our model works.
Let us start with an example.
Let's say there is a dataset containing data on
many different aspects of flowers like petal lengths or color.
Let's say you're building a model to determine if a flower is one
of two commonest species based on measurable details.
You could use model accuracy or how often your model predicts
the character species to evaluate if
your trained model will be good at solving that task.
To evaluate models, we often use a statistical metrics like accuracy.
Here are a few examples of different metrics that you can use.
Some are more common than others.
For example, precision or F1 score,
but there are more that you can explore.
Please note that this is not a one-and-done process.
It's an iterative process until you get the results you're looking for.
Based on how the model evaluation goes,
you may find that you need to go back to previous steps that we discussed.
You might need to change the configuration of parameters of
the training model or possibly even choosing different model.
You might have to tweak the model or make adjustments to your data.
You might even rethink how you are framing the problem.
At some point, you will have a model which meets your need.
Now you can use the model.